got my masters in management and
Leadership and then I rounded it out
with my doctorate in business
administration so uh with an emphasis in
in technology actually um so after that
uh it was about uh
maybe a year and a half ago maybe maybe
two years ago that I found Michael
Hyatt's book um living forward and that
book really talks about making a life so
with an emphasis it's funny because it
actually starts off having you write
your own eulogy so you really start
thinking about where you want to be and
so I started evaluating what I was doing
and even though it was all technology
related and I had been doing that for a
long time really where I found my
fulfillment was in helping develop other
people Empower them to perform better
and so that's when I decided that what I
needed to be doing was really taking the
leadership skills that I had and pouring
those into other people so
that I could help benefit them right so
that's when I started welled and that's
what I've been doing for the last uh
mons September so about nine months so
about nine so it's a very very very new
company um that you started up there and
so um you know because I guess
leadership seems to be your your your
Niche because you've mentioned it um
several times uh you know what about you
makes you a great leader and and two
questions so what makes you a good
leader and then the other question is
where did you learn that leadership from
and you know um and
[Music]
hey how's it going my friends my name is
Ryan Perez older and founder of bowai
creative and the host of The Hustle Zone
and folks I've been working working day
and night you know because this
Magazine's coming out in October 1st and
we're trying to get this thing regularly
scheduled so that we have content every
day so I've been working with the
content creators uh I want to host some
of their shows during the week so if you
are a person that wants to have their
own show you probably want to hit me up
you probably want to become a writer for
the hustles all magazine because I may
have a slot for you um so that we can
help produce content every day you know
we want to produce like really good
content and um so uh folks this is the
hustle Zone this is where we expand the
crop we get to know people beyond the
success beyond the Beyond um
you know the success stories uh but you
know we we want to see everything we
want to see what what makes these
entrepreneurs tick so I'm super super
happy for um where we've come I mean
it's almost been a year since we've been
doing the videos I mean it's been over a
year of us Pro promoting content um and
creating content but uh it's been almost
a year we actually did the the hustle
Zone um format so I am super excited for
that and um so who's in the house
tonight I don't know I've tagged people
so like folks if you don't mind to share
share share share share and I'm going to
get um I'm just going to going to share
to life talk Nation these are my peeps
you know these are a bunch of if you if
you're a live streamer you definitely
need to be a part of that group because
uh life talk nation is definitely going
to um promote your stuff they're
going looks like feature using is too
oh I've been blocked from
sharing I have been blocked from sharing
Shing okay so anyway I don't doesn't
look like I can share
today but um
regardless we are going to um hold on a
second here let's see if I can find a
different way from sharing so who's in
the room let me know Ryan Perez in the
house um let just go to live talk Nation
we got three people in the room so say
something say
hi
uh okay so I've I've I've shared I'm
good to go now so now folks uh hustle
Zone
gear uh you want to make sure that you
get your hustle Zone gear at hustle
zone.com or not hustle zone. clo I
believe so um it's a it's a great place
to find good merch uh from get that tea
get that tea produces it so I'm super
happy to be with it you know you know
partnered up with them and um you know
I've also put donate links um like you
know because you know we're not doing
this for for you know like out of thin
air like money doesn't grow trees so we
definitely need your support so uh you
know feel free that if you feel that
we're producing really good content to
please donate
donate um and yeah so I don't see many
people in the room tonight which is uh
weird maybe it's just my system here
because I see people here but I just
don't see their comments and I normally
greet people around this time so that's
okay I'm going to tell you guys about a
person that um who's going to be part of
the hustle Zone tonight and he uh you
know just hit me up randomly and said he
wanted to be on the show because he saw
something that uh we were doing and and
U he said he wanted to be a part of it
and um you know I was thrown off because
I wasn't sure what wellfed you know LLC
meant you know and from what I
understood is that wellfed was like I
thought he was like feeding kids in
Africa or somewhere around the world um
so I was just like oh we're going to
talk about you know some social
entrepreneuring tonight but he he has
let me know that it's not that's not it
was the first inclination but it's not
that's not what he's all about uh and
then when cuz and I was thrown off
because today I was trying to figure out
because I didn't really do much prep
because I didn't I didn't know him I we
just set it up and I was pretty
proactive and getting him on the show
and then you know I put out a post today
and he he uh he he he uh um he shares it
and then he
says Doc's going to be or Dr Dr uh Josh
is going to be on tonight's hustle zone
I'm like oh so he's feeding kids in
Africa and he's also a
doctor
so he just told me that's not that's not
you know he's not a medical doctor so
he'll explain all of that later on
tonight so I was I I was just thrown off
trying to figure it out and then I asked
him to send me a head
shot and the headshot he had was like
this e we little photo and I couldn't do
nothing with the head shot it was
pixelated and uh but realizing that the
head shot was on his Facebook and it was
a nice picture with him and his his wife
or fiance I'm not sure so I'm going to
have to ask him that tonight but you
know so I was just I was just confused
today I was like I don't know who I'm
being tonight so going to have to like
ask him some questions before we get
onto this call because I was just
confused um I'm joking but uh no but he
seems like a like I in the green room he
seems a pretty um pretty good guy and um
I'm super excited to have him because
you know there he this guy specializes
in leadership and you know what you
could be dumb as a door knob you can
have no
money uh but the people that move this
world are
leaders you know and Leadership is very
important you know and I really you know
it's so funny he was kind of tell me a
little bit about his story before we got
on and I shouldn't have asked the
questions because I I normally don't
like to ask um before I get onto the
show but you know he said you know he he
he said something about moving up the
ranks and whenever someone moves up the
ranks it's not because they are goody
two shoes it's because they know how to
be team players and you know having good
leadership skills you got to be a great
team player you have to be able to do
the job that someone asked you to do if
they say jump on your on jump and do 10
jumping jacks you do
11 yeah you look you look pretty cool
but you're not a team player because
you're trying to show people up you know
if someone ask you to do 10 Jumping
Jacks and you do
nine then you just look like you're lazy
you could do the extra the extra right
but if you do
10 you you know how to follow orders but
you also are playing you're you're
you're a team player that's in my eyes I
think someone that knows how to listen
to other people and lets people talk and
lets people air out their concerns but
also knows when to talk and knows when
to instruct people I think good
leadership but I'm not an expert at
leadership this guy is and so we're
going to get him on here so everyone
give it up for and and folks if you guys
have any questions um just type in
slq and you can um ask questions and
then we got uh Anthony Davis in the
house now I'm so sad that I cannot share
this out to live talk Nation Facebook I
don't understand why you guys have
blocked me from this feature shame on
you that's why I'm creating hustle own
TV in 1 month okay but um that being
said um everyone give it up for Joshua
Nelson how's it going my friend oh it's
going great Ryan thanks for having me
what did you think about that
introduction I liked it man authentic
real you know straight to the point uh
you covered a lot of good points in
there so I enjoyed it yeah that's
awesome see I didn't think you expecting
me to say all that but
he's like what am I coming on this
hustle zone for this guy's so boring in
the pre inter viw The Green Room but um
I try to save the excitement for the
show rather than be behind the scenes
but um how are you doing my friend oh
I'm doing real well you know it's it's
uh it's been a busy week but it's been a
good week so I'm excited to to meet with
you tonight and wrap things up before
the weekend here awesome awesome now
Jonathan or not Jonathan Joshua
um I want to let you know that we have a
few Traditions the first tradition um
for the hustle zone is that we ask you
what your story is so can you kindly
tell us from the very beginning like
when you were born like I want to know
the your full story um set go I'm joking
no right yeah but let us know all right
so I was born and raised in Newport
Richie Florida well I was born in
Newport Richie Florida I was raised in
Mazer toown uh which is about 40 minutes
from there maybe give or take it's a
small little town uh and you know I I
spent the first few years there and then
uh my parents wound up getting a divorce
um and my father moved away so I spent
my time kind of commuting back and forth
between Arkansas and Florida uh Summers
Christmas you know how that typically
can go um and I I did that throughout uh
my school School career when I graduated
high school I decided you know I'm going
to go into college but I got to be
honest at that point in my life I wasn't
very responsible or mature so I kind of
blew it off uh and just floated around
for about a year I I think I had a
point6 GPA something to that
effect um so what did I do I I looked
for opportunities and uh the Marine
Corps is where I decided to go so I went
into the Marine Corps but again didn't
have much focus in directions went in
open contract which basically means they
pick your job for you uh so I I went in
there and uh they chose computers for me
so I was a computer guy inside the
Marine Corps and I did that for four
years I spent some time in South
Carolina Paris Island for boot camp I
went out to uh the Mojave desert in
California at 29 Palms to get my
training then I spent some time at camp
geers and most of my career was at camp
June and so I did that um in there I was
a data network technician I was a
tactical data networker and information
systems Chief uh so it was a great
experience got a lot of uh life
experience for sure really quick um but
when I got out I decided to get out
because while I was in I got married and
I had uh well I had one kid and I when I
got out I was eight months into my
second kid uh so he was about to be born
and so I got out the Marine Corps and I
decided to stay in the technology field
because you know again my uh my ex-wife
there was eight months pregnant so we um
I got a job with the neelen company
which is the TV ratings company if
you're not familiar with it and I did
yeah I did that for about 13 months um
and that was a that was a really nice
job I liked it a lot the problem was I
didn't know when I was working tomorrow
till 10:00 tonight right so it made it
real hard to to progress or do anything
with the with the family go I wanted to
go back to school um so I managed to get
my associates while I was in the Marine
Corps my daughter when she was born
really spurred me into action there uh
but with that job I didn't have time so
I wound up getting a job with the local
school system and from there um I kind
of worked my way up like you said
through the ranks earlier um and so
while I was doing that I also went back
to school and I managed to get uh my
Bachelor's in Business Administration
then I went on and got my masters in
management and Leadership and then I
rounded it out with my doctor in
Business Administration so with an
emphasis in in technology actually um so
after that uh it was about uh
maybe a year and a half ago maybe maybe
two years ago that I found Michael
Hyatt's book um living forward and that
book really talks about making a life so
with an emph it's funny because it
actually starts off having you write
your own eulogy so you really start
thinking about where you want to be and
so I started evaluating what I was doing
and even though it was all technology
related and I had been doing that for a
long time really where I found my
fulfillment was in helping develop other
people Empower them to perform better
and so that's when I decided that what I
needed to be doing was really taking the
leadership skills that I had and pouring
those into other people so
that I could help benefit them right so
that's when I started well fed
and that's what I've been doing for the
last uh months September so about nine
months so about nine so it's a very very
very new company um that you started up
there and so um you know because I guess
leadership seems to be your your your
Niche because you've mentioned it um
several times uh you know what about you
makes you a great leader and and two
questions so what makes you a good
leader and then the other question is
where did you learn that leadership from
and you know um and was that a quality
that you had even when you were you know
when you were a kid or when you were
young like did you always have that that
capability of leading
people that's a great question so I I've
been told that I was a natural leader
but I think I think it's you know
refined and defined as you go um so so
to answer your first question what helps
me be that great leaders um really I
think it's your mindset um I always
think of myself as serving anyone and
rather than me thinking that I'm in
charge or over uh people that report to
me I look at it in the opposite uh
Direction whereas I'm serving them right
because without them there's no need for
me so that that's my mindset that
servant leadership mentality and I think
that's what's really helped me be able
to continue to grow and continue to do
well in the leadership capacity because
it's it's not about me um and to your to
I'm sorry what was the second the second
part of that question again second
question is um did you where did you
learn leadership right okay so obviously
I have my my educational background but
um you know really I I I directed back
to my moral compass you know I'm I'm a
Christian so a big part of me is uh
biblical uh how Jesus would do things
and really that Golden Rule of you know
do for others what you would want done
for you and so that's that's really how
I try to try to lead I try to just think
about what would be best for the
organization and the people who I'm I'm
serving and then do
that now um we have a question from
Anthony Davis but we're GNA before we uh
get to his question
uh when did you realized that you had um
the gift to be a leader like when did it
turn turn on for you like oh my God like
I got this amazing gift let me let me
use it to my
benefit I'd say I was pretty young I was
pretty young I can remember uh just kind
of taking charge from the get-go um you
know in situations where other people
may C take time to pause and and
hesitate um you know I often joke you
know with the fight ORF flight I I often
say I don't have a flight response I
just jump into action um so so it was
early on you know but I can remember one
time I I learned the difference between
leadership and boss I think and this may
sound odd but I think on the playground
when I was probably about five or six um
I was playing with my friends and I
remember I was I was being pretty bossy
I
I I was like we're GNA play this and
they they straight out had told me uh
you know they like you picked all week
we're not playing that and they ran off
and did their own thing and I realized
right then and there I was like you know
I can't always dictate the situation it
can't be about me it can't be uh what
what I want I can't just direct life so
I think that really started the Shaving
of of you know do help other people have
a good time and and do their best but
really taking account what they're
looking for too yeah yeah and I mean I
was I wasn't a great leader when I was a
kid I'll tell you that and I was I but I
wanted to be like I just didn't know how
and I hated those kids that would
um that would pick all the time I'd be
like okay why you got you're not the
boss of me exactly right why do you got
to do that so it's very interesting that
you at a young age was able to recognize
that that you know that's a power that
you have so you you know and you know it
kind of smart of you as well because
you're like oh the probability of me
keeping my
friends you know like eight eight out of
nine times I'll be able to get away with
having my own way but you know what you
know one time out of eight we'll let
them have their way and then everyone
will be married
so yeah I mean every relationship's a
little bit give and take right so yeah
for sure now are there areas where you
know what about you being a student like
how when you were kid like how how how
was high school for you and how was how
was elementary for you yeah uh well you
know I moved around well I bounced
around in schools a little bit
especially in the elementary middle time
frame a lot due to U my parents you know
having split I spent a year in Arkansas
with my father and uh I was in uh
private school for a couple years public
school for a couple years then back in
private school um I landed in so you
know I got I got a lot of different
experiences got to meet a lot of
different people and I think you learned
to acclimate um to your surroundings a
little bit and so that that's definitely
helped in my leadership journey in high
school uh kind of a similar story I I
started off um more I I'd have to say
almost more of a loner um I mean I had
my friends my my little group that I
would um communicate with and you know
hang out with but as the years progress
I mean by my by the end of my senior
year I had been just building up
relationships getting to know people and
I actually got nominated for one of
those Mr High School awards you know I
didn't win it but just being nominated
was kind of a neat neat way to go out of
high school mhm that's awesome now
um I'm going to ask uh Anthony's
question here uh Anthony
says Define sincerity it's a two-part
question and then the second part of
that question is do you find that there
is a lack of sincerity in the world
today man wow that's that's some good
stuff right there sincerity I think I
think sinc it is meaning what what
you're saying right you you can tell
when somebody's figting empathy or
pretending you know I I can pretend to
care about what you're saying I can I
can coddle you for lack of a better term
right and just go along with with what
you say and plate your feelings but but
that that's insincere people see through
that if you if you don't have that heart
for people it comes across so I think
sincerity is is backing up what you say
with your actions um and showing people
how much you care rather than just
saying it it's it's walking the walk
right rather than just talking the talk
mhm yeah now um getting back to you as U
now growing up as a young lad when if
you could look back and I normally ask
this at the end but like if you could
look back at your cuz it seemed like you
had a
pretty um you know pretty okay childhood
in in terms of you having a good sense
of awareness and and whatnot but is
there anything that you would have
changed about your childhood um to help
put you on a higher
Plateau um today or would you not change
anything uh the ladder you know I've
thought about that a lot and I think our
life experiences really help sculpt us
into who we are and and quite honestly I
like who I am so uh the even the bumps
along the way the rocky Parts I wouldn't
trade them you know they were hard at
the time but they helped refine me you
know there's a there's a quote that I I
can't remember right now who said it but
um it says our our situations don't
Define us but they give us the
opportunity to refine ourselves you know
and and I just love that that's awesome
now uh now going into the Marine Corps
um what were some of your
challenges um because I mean like it's
discipline right you got to learn to
discipline yourself and um and you being
a leader and having that you know that
that knack for
leadership than having someone you know
pretty much tell you that you're not
you're not a leader yet so you know calm
down yeah you know that that must
destroyed your your ego coming in you
know it probably could have if I weren't
so stubborn you know that's that's one
of the things I I I've often heard
people joke about if you want to see if
I'm going to do something just pretty
much tell me I can't uh or I won't U
it's kind of a running joke but um and I
think that that played a lot into I you
know when I was younger uh especially I
always felt like I had something to
prove um I think I chose the Marine
Corps just because other people in my
family had gone in a couple other
branches Army Air Force and I was like
well I'm gonna I'm going to go in the
Marines because that seems like one of
one of the hardest ones right so I I
just wanted to take myself that next
level I think that's why I started down
the career for my doctorate too you know
I I just wanted to try and get to that
top
Echelon and
um hold on one second so you just you
you just kind of challenge yourself with
uh what people were kind of throwing at
you and and that's kind of what help you
plateau through your ranks Etc is that
correct right you know I I I always try
to challenge myself my goal in life is
to be content ENT but not complacent
right I'm always I'm always trying to be
happy and fine with where I'm at but
never never just rest there yeah there's
always there's always another step to
take and and I'm always looking for it
so what what are your goals now then you
know um you not being you know always
striving for something better or greater
like what are the things that are that
you do not have that you that you wish
to have well you know it's not much
tangible things really I just want to I
just want to make a significant impact
in in people's lives um you know I I've
gotten your your quote on quote uh
definition of success you know I've done
well in that regard but really what
brings me the most joy is helping other
people succeed developing their skills
empowering them you know because because
who wants to be at the top by themselves
right so I want to pour into other
people and bring them along for the ride
or help them get wherever they want to
go that that is such a super superficial
answer I mean most people don't think
that they you know that you know most
people are like yeah I want to change
the world but hold on let me go buy
myself another boat and I'm going to go
traveling you know so like what makes
like and I'm not saying that it's
superficial I'm I'm joking because I
mean I just want like what's the Deep
there's there's there's there's a deep
rooted
passion that leads people to want to do
or to serve others like what's in this
for
you I mean as crazy as it sounds I I
don't have a lot other than that's just
the my core um you know I think you see
that a lot of times with with people um
that that go in the service or you know
I I just really
enjoy helping and empowering others you
know that's that that's what I really
realized when I read that book U Michael
H's living for it and I mean obviously I
have you know financial needs and I have
um you know obligations that I have I
have my bills I have things like that so
I do need a certain threshold of income
but I don't need excess because what am
I what am I going to do with it you know
I mean I can sit in a bank account and
and gain interest and and I can buy an
extra toy I mean as long as my family's
taking care of I'm I'm
content now tell tell me about your
family so
uh uh I you were talking you saying that
you have kids so uh so tell me a little
bit about your family yeah so I have
five kids three of them are my
biologically and the other two are my
girlfriends so
um uh I consider them mine you know so
five all together they range from ages
one there's twins that are one um then I
have a 5-year-old a 10-year-old and uh
well she'll be 12 next week so running
about a decade worth of different ages
there holy moly so a lot of kids and and
how do you with you being a business
person entrepreneur how do you how do
you manage all of that family life and
then you know business as
well yeah it it can be a challenge
sometimes I'm not going to lie this week
was extremely busy and it was definitely
challenging this week but you know I
think it's all about knowing your
priorities and what's important to you
and and really
committing uh time management so if you
say I'm going to spend this amount of
time on this project know that when that
time is up you need to stop right
because work's always going to be there
and same same with when you need to
start work's always going to be there
right so you need to you need to make
sure you dedicate the the appropriate
time for that but then make sure
remember that I mean one of the biggest
things you can do is impact the child
right because that's the Next Generation
that's after you're gone so and I I just
love spending time with the kids so um I
I I try to dedicate myself in both areas
and I'll tell you Ashley my girlfriend
she helps out amazingly you know um when
I'm when I need a little extra time to
do something like this or do something
with the job she steps in and and really
provides that support for me so it's
team it's teamwork now have you guys
ever you know because I know
entrepreneurialism especially when you
have a a 9-month-old you know baby your
company um and it it takes a lot like
and I when I was young I had a business
Mentor that referred to you know the
making of uh making of a baby
to uh running your own business because
you know you you put all your effort
into this you know this thing that needs
support needs finances it needs cash
flow it needs you know the right people
um and it needs dedication so you know I
have always been an entrepreneur and
when I was I had a fiance and we would
argue you know what was
important and um and even though at the
time she was willing
to go through the paces sometimes she
wasn't happy about it you know in your
situation were you ever in those
situations where you you've had to put
Priority for the business first over
your
family yeah you know I'm trying to think
back so I can definitely tell you
wellfed that hasn't come up um but this
isn't my first uh business I actually
had one back uh years ago when I was in
my early 20s I started my own computer
repair business it was on the side of my
computer work back then and it it did
very well it took off um it it took off
to the point where I couldn't do my
full-time job that that business and I
think I was in school at the time for
either my bachelor's or or my masters
one of the two and you know with with
the kids and everything everything was
just piling on you
know I really had to take a step back
look at the situation and say what am I
willing to cut because I can't you know
that I'm only one person I can only do
so much and I I learned a good part
about uh time management and life
balance there because something had to
go and I had to ask myself what is that
is it going to be you know my college
that I'm trying to better myself with is
it going to be my family absolutely not
is it going to be my full-time career or
is it going to be uh my my business and
at the time because I was young and I
and I was probably looking for that
sense of security I stayed with the
full-time it job that had the benefits
and the nice security you know if I
could go back then like I said earlier I
wouldn't change it but you know that's
one of those things you always wonder
what if um but so I I Clos down that
business because it really did get to
the point where I was going to have to
choose one thing over another and and I
had to make that choice and that's the
way yeah and and do you think that
because there are entrepreneurs out
there that are not sleeping that are you
know that are spending night and day
working on their business grinding and
hustling
um do you think that's healthy and do
you think that um do you think that you
know with what you know about leadership
and and whatnot do you think that um
it's possible that you can balance
everything I think everybody has a
capacity that that they need to be aware
of right everybody it's not a one- siiz
fits-all some people can handle a little
bit more some people can run off of
sleep a little or a little less sleep it
really depends on your situation but I
do think that it's very important to
know your limits and not push
yourself so you need to challenge
yourself past those but you need to not
set yourself up with something that you
can't maintain if you if you set
yourself to perform something outside of
your capabilities for a very extended
period of time you're going to
fail you can't continue pushing pushing
pushing pushing without a minute to take
a rest and think of it like when you
work out right you know you can push
yourself you know bench press increase
that weight your muscles are tearing
they're ripping eventually you run out
of steam you need to rest and then that
you know you take that period of rest
your muscles get stronger you can do
more right but you always require a
period of rest in order to be able to
continue on you can't push 100% all the
time without without burning out MH now
have you always been good at surrounding
yourself your with the right people
right
friends I can tell you right now that
was quick yeah um I have definitely made
some poor choices in that area you know
I've learned over the years that's
that's key and vital um you know that's
one of the things Ashley's amazing with
her support uh with wed and with just me
in general um but you know I didn't
always have the support structure and
maybe that's part of why I always felt
you know like when people told me I
couldn't do it I I needed to um but but
I've made some poor choices but luckily
I've had some good people in my life too
and and it's balanced out and now you
know now I I have a little stricter
criteria for who I incorporated into my
life right yeah I I guess it's all about
being an adult and knowing how to move
forward because you know some I I I mean
I still know people that doing the same
old stuff that they were doing in high
school and you know they you know but I
have to admire them because they're
Troopers I mean you know someone with
dedication they got a lot of dedication
CU they want to stick to stick to the
image or the ego that they have you know
kind of like they're a superhero right
because you know when you're
you're when you're a teenager you know
you you you have like for me it was a
bandana or baggy pants and you know or
for other kids it's like yeah I change
my hair color all the time right so
they're they're frying their hair all
the time and you know sticking with that
but you know as they get older the
people that are really dedicated and
maintaining their identity um what they
think is their identity um they stick
with it but the thing is is it's funny
that they don't change but they don't
change they're not learning they're not
they're not growing and and and whatnot
so you know what ways have you changed
um you know throughout throughout the
years yeah well first first let me say
just one quick point to what you just
said right even though they decide not
to change they're not Chang the world
around them is changing so if they're
not changing to adapt to it they're
they're going to fall farther and
farther behind but um I have definitely
changed a lot and I'll tell you the
biggest motivator that that changed me
was was my daughter being born and then
subsequent kids um you know it really
took me from boy of manhood if you will
uh before she came along I was just
living for me doing doing my own thing
and all of my answers tonight would be
completely different I could promise you
that but uh she set me on a path of
really
discovering who I am and what I wanted
to do and um that's that she's been one
of the greatest motivators and
encouragements you know at least that's
where it started my other kids have also
pushed me along the way but but she lit
the initial fuse right so yeah and and
in what way like kind of Des because
because it became about more than me um
when when it's just me if I make if I
make a stupid decision or I decide to
you know not go out not try to better
myself or waste my resources or waste my
talents that's just me I'm only
impacting me once I became responsible
for another human life you know it
really really hit me hard you know I
want to make sure that my child um and
all my children wind up better better
than than I was I feel like that's my
goal as a parent is to to help them be
better than I
am now uh when it came now that you've
started a wellfed tell us a little bit
about the company and um you know what
like you know tell us your inspiration
for the company and how it all got
started and what it's all about yeah
well I'll tell you like I said the
inspiration came from the book uh living
forward by Michael hayatt uh really got
me focused on the life plan and really
helped me narrow down what it was that I
enjoyed about what I was doing and that
was you know helping other people get
better and and develop
um so that that really set me on the
path um and so wellfed is our core focus
is helping other people achieve their
definition of success because we know
not everyone has the same one some
people are perfectly content you know um
being a being a homemaker raising kids
other people want to be CEOs of
companies and some people just want to
be somewhere in the middle and whatever
that is we want to help people get there
so we do it in a variety of ways we do
do one-on-one coaching you know um that
that's a big thing for us we do team
building so groups of 20 or less we we
have or uh activities and and sessions
that we do to help strengthen those
bonds and then uh we go all the way up
to motivational spe speeches um at
conferences and for organizations um we'
come in and just kind of give give
inspiration for those things that's
that's awesome and um
we were talking about leadership but um
from your definition now um you being in
this place you know what is your
definition of of being a leader so my
definition of leadership I think there's
really only one leadership style I know
a lot of books will tell you there's
there's multiple I think there's one
leadership style and many management
techniques um but I think the only true
leadership style is servant leadership I
think if you're not out there working
for the people that that work for you
then you're doing something wrong there
may be different ways in which to to
handle that role such you know sometimes
you have to be a little more
authoritative sometimes you can give
people uh a diplomatic type approach and
sometimes you can convince them that you
know of doing a certain thing so there's
a lot of different management techniques
and ways to apply leadership but I think
there's really only that one style of
servant
leadership yeah
and would anyone try to debate you
because I'm sure yeah I'm sure some I'm
sure some people would and you know uh
there I've met I've met people that have
different viewpoints of course um but
typically I find they'll they may get
work done but when you put a side by
side usually they don't get as much
effort out of their employees so while
they may be productive I'm going to be
more productive while they may be
successful I'm going to have more
success and that's not a result me
that's a result of me caring about the
team and the team performing because
they want to re reciprocate that care
okay I'm going to give you a
scenario you
are I you just walked into a company
with 30 people that you do not know okay
um and you
know but you you're asked to you know
manage the the the team for one day you
know from hour to hour what would you do
so if I have one day and that's it and
then I'm out of there correct yeah so
the very first thing I'm going to do is
I'm going to bring the team together I'm
gonna I'm GNA give them a little bit of
background about me I'm going to
introduce myself and I'm going to ask
them two simple questions I'm going to
say what's working what's not working
okay the things that are working our
strengths we're going to focus our
efforts on that today the things that
are not working what we're going to do
is we're going to not ignore those what
we're going to do is we are going to
talk about potential Alternatives or the
reason why we're doing those
things and we're going to spend that
first hour doing that because in that
first hour if we identify tasks that
we've been doing just because we've
always done them or you know there's no
real definitive reason we're going to
cut those why are we wasting our time on
things that aren't productive I'm going
to you know and so we're going to take
suggestions we're going to look at
different things that we can really
eliminate or get rid of things that are
our hurdles and blocking our ways um and
look for those opportunities to focus on
our core strengths you know there's a
lot of research that says if you focus
on strengths you will get a lot more
results than if you focus on trying to
eliminate your
weaknesses wow and um so and then after
that what would you do okay so once once
we've uh you know focused on our
strengths for that morning since I only
have one day I think we would have a a
company lunch or group lunch uh so I
would go ahead and order in food for
everyone because you know part of
especially when I only have one day it
it's really getting their commitment to
work work hard for me right they they
want to work for something so we've I I
took the time out to listen to them hear
their points of view taking their
feedback now I'm taking care of their
physical needs right and during that
lunch we're going to talk about okay so
what what have we seen this morning have
we increased productivity is it the same
is it is it worse right or maybe one of
those things that we took out and said
was unnecessary we've found now is
actually a key process um and so if
that's the case we're going to adjust
and adapt and if we need to add
something back in we'll do that and
otherwise if things are moving along
better than they've ever been we're
going to go full steam ahead and just
keep focusing on those strengths and
really take business to the next level
as much as we can in a day now the day
is over what do you do day is over uh so
I you know I gather up the employees and
we just have an after action report
right we talk about hey you know this is
what we did today this is Success that
we achieved here are the here are the
high points that we had so I'm going to
leave I'm not going to be here tomorrow
but now it's your job to carry that on
right you saw what we're capable of you
saw what you're team can do it wasn't
because of me it was because of your
efforts right so me not being here
shouldn't produce any less results so
tomorrow you guys come in here you do
even better than you did today because I
know you can yeah that belief in them
makes them believe in themselves and
they just you know they they get a fire
in them and they and they want to prove
it to you even though they have no
obligation to do it to me because I'm
I'm
gone do you ever have you ever dealt
with people that are just not skilled um
because I've always been under the
impression that you know for any
business to run you need to be you need
to only have skilled people but you know
ever so often you know you you you you
hire people and you find out that
they're just not cut you know but what
if there's no one available to hire
again like you know hiring and firing
employees is just expensive you know
yeah what would you what would you say
would be the
um the the golden the Golden Rule in
dealing with people that are
inexperienced but you know you want high
yield okay so I would say the golden
rule for that is to what you would do
for anybody do for everybody and what I
mean by that right I'm going to say one
more time what you would do for anybody
do for everybody so
a lot of times what I've seen in
organizations is when somebody isn't
high yield or isn't highly skilled they
get kind of Forgotten or pushed to the
side right I can't deal with that person
they're just too much effort they're not
going to produce for me they're not
going to do work so I'm going to push
them over here and basically ignore them
not give them any of my attention I'm
not saying that they should give special
attention but what you would do for
another employee you have an expectation
or should have an expectation that you
would do that for them as well so
because if you forget about them then
they're going to become disengaged right
if they're trying and not succeeding at
least they're engaged you can work with
a person like that you can work with
somebody who's trying once they become
just disengaged and don't want to aren't
a part of the team you you you have a
much harder battle right it's it's like
keeping an employee versus recruiting an
employeee that that that's the challenge
if if you have somebody that wants to do
well
you can work and get them to that point
if you have somebody that's just there
sitting there collecting the paycheck
and you're ignoring them that's what
they're going to do people will only
rise to the expectation you put on them
um you know yeah so do you think that um
like so but but if you have like a a
monthly goal like I mean this is worst
case scenario here I mean it's
hypothetical but you have a goal that
you have to reach within 15 days you
know how can you get the most out of
that that person so that you know so
that you're not you're not going out of
business or you're not meeting your
benchmarks because I mean it could be
tough especially with different learning
styles and all that good stuff so I've
got two answers for that one um I had
some great advice one time that said
employees are like a bag of those
assorted rubber bands right it's not the
job of a leader to stretch everyone to
the same distance or same capability but
it is a Leader's job to stretch everyone
as far as as they can stretch so if you
do that I think you're going to get
success but the second part and and a
part that a lot of people don't talk
about is as a leader in that role part
of your job is to help employees get to
where they want to be or where they fit
so if somebody really can't perform the
job or they just aren't fitting in with
the the company's culture or or it's
just not a good fit you know there's
nothing wrong with coaching them and
talking to them and say are are you
happy here is this what you want to do
because from what I can tell and from
your the skill you put forth I don't
think this is a right fit for you I want
you to be successful and that may not be
here I I think it's okay to be honest
with people and and give them that and I
think they would respect that a lot more
than stringing them along and shoving
them in a
corner yeah because I think dead weight
is dead weight I think that people don't
really you know see the implicit cost of
having extra you know because having
extra resources around right
uh if they're not if the resources are
not being used you're you know you have
waste yeah and so you know you have a
bunch of people in your your office
doing nothing and just doing the minimal
you know it's best in my humble opinion
it's if you can't utilize them like you
said if you can't make use of to the to
to a point of where they're willing to
go you know it's just dead weight and we
get so attached to people that we forget
the science of business and we right you
know we forget yeah go ahead it's a it's
a flip of the mindset right we we think
that we're doing them a favor by keeping
them on but we're not we're holding them
back if this isn't where they're
supposed to be if they're not performing
well here if this isn't something that
satisfies them we are doing them a
disservice by keeping them if we if we
can help release them out to do what
they want to do what they what their
life mission or what their skill set is
that that's a favor to them that's how
we serve them yeah now um so Anthony
Davis if I don't know if you're still
here it's really really bad that I can't
share but if you guys are part of live
talk Nation please share it there um you
know I normally share in that group but
I can't share tonight because I've been
banned and I don't spam I don't think I
spam maybe my vegan stuff but you know I
don't
spam um
so I don't know why I'm being penalized
but anthy Davis says um there's nothing
wrong with wanting to make your life
better by helping
others have a better life it's kind of
like the George Bailey effect uh George
Bailey from It's a Wonderful Life when
one of my favorite movies yeah that's uh
Ashley Elizabeth Lutz said Anthony Davis
that's actually one of Joshua's favorite
movies so you have someone in in the
crowd there that knows you very well um
so when he when he got a chance to to
see how much of impact he had on the
world around him it made him realize
that he had a wonderful life yeah that's
uh that's that's pretty cool uh I'm just
going through the comments here that's
that's it for comments so we got eight
minutes until the show is complo so I'm
going to ask you a few questions and um
you know I want to ask you more
questions and get um you know but you
know I I think that you're you're you
would be a good candidate to write some
stuff on the magazine and to put some
leadership shows together for the hust
on we we definitely want to collaborate
with you my friend because you have't
really you have a good you have complete
it it's almost like what you're saying
is more complete than you know what I've
heard from others when it comes to
leadership because I think that people
try to complicate it when really it's
just common sense right
um but that being said what's your
favorite uh
dessert oh man put me on the spot it it
it depends on the day but you know what
I always seem to go for and love it I
don't know what it's called it's like
dirt pie you take Oreos and chocolate
pudding and throw some gummy worms in
there I think with some Cool Whip man
it's
amazing it's always delicious it sounds
delicious I wish I could have it now but
I can't due to my diet o but uh
uh Game of Thrones or Breaking
Bad oh tough I I've only seen a few
episodes of either to be honest with you
uh can I say maybe The Walking Dead can
I can I hop over yeah you could yeah The
Walking Dead all right I follow I
followed that one what is it about The
Walking Dead that you like so much you
know I think I think it's just the
development of the story and maybe if I
got it more into the other ones I would
too but you know it starts out with the
the humanity and and you just see the
different layers I guess of humanity and
and how how people interact with each
other and and you kind of wonder how you
would do in a world like that I guess
yeah and um when it uh Michael Jackson
or
Prince oh man these are great questions
man uh I think I gotta go I think I
gotta go with MJ Michael Jackson I think
Michael Jackson yeah I would have to say
Michael Jackson he's my favorite I like
them both but you know Michael Jackson's
my favorite uh
and if you had a magic
wand and you
could replace something right now what
would you
replace ah man um I had a magic one and
I could replace something you know what
I do I'd get all that water out of
freaking uh Houston Dallas and all all
the Texas area there yeah that that has
been pretty rough watching the videos
and watching people lose their pets you
know uh a lady just wased uh you know
her her her her grand for grandchildren
and her um and and and her parents
so it it you know it you never know
right you just I look at my son every
day and I'm like you know you know I try
to I try to teach him what I need to
teach him and I say just in case
anything happens that you know I just
want to make sure that he he will be all
right because like you know life could
be gone like like that so you know uh
we're praying for all those who are
suffering in Texas I know there's a lot
of people in Texas that are in my
network um you know we're praying for
you and and um and and and folks if you
guys looking to donate please go to the
Red Cross and um the uh then 41 Sports
uh Anthony mclan had Dallas Cowboy who's
part also part of the the the the hustle
Zone he has two the top Texas 41 so if
you type in that hashtag you'll uh that
will lead you down the path to donating
cuz he's out there every day donating
water and and all kinds of things so
please support you know support the
Texans and even if it's $5 um do
something to help you know your fellow
American um and the
last the last question I was going to
ask you tell us about your event oh yeah
so uh what we have going on September
23rd it's our uh 2017 tap the well
leadership conference uh the cool thing
about this leadership conference is if
you're local you can come attend but if
you're not we have a live simal cast
going on so you can get a ticket for
that um it's going to be an awesome
event we've got live music eight amazing
speakers that are going to be talking on
different topics from engaging with
disengaged employees uh scaling your
business leading by example building a
healthy team culture all of it really
focused on uh developing leadership that
lasts right something that's going to
last beyond you building that leadership
Legacy so it's really easy to get
tickets if you want them it's just we
made a simple URL for you it's ww.
tinyurl.com
slap thewell it's $50 for the live event
or $30 for access to that live stream
that's awesome so uh I was going to
anthy Davis said hey Joshua you never
asked
answered the second part of my question
he said the sincerity yeah do do you
think that there's a lack of sincerity
in the world
today I don't think there's a lack of
sincerity I think what we've run into is
uh a we've allowed fear to kind of take
over um in a lot of instances fear of
either rejection or what people will
think or or repercussions maybe and so I
think that heart is still there in
people I think people want to be sincere
but I think sometimes they Shield
themselves with either sarcasm or or
some other emotion um so I I think you
know Gandhi you know hit it on the nail
of the head when he said be the change
you want to see in the world right so
regardless of what's going on around you
we have a responsibility to show our
sincerity and I I can only hope that
that would Inspire somebody else to do
the same
thing yeah exactly and uh that's a great
answer we have two minutes left we got
to do
um we have to do one more thing this is
a a tradition at the hustle Zone and I
and I apologize in
advance okay okay so I'm going to do a
call and response and I'm going to ask
you to scream hustle Zone as loud as you
can all right I'll do my best so you're
going to wake up the babies and all
kinds of things um so um so one two
three welcome to the hustle Zone oh too
early sorry that was too early man all
right try again and you got to do hustle
Zone okay so all right one more time so
welcome to the hustle
Zone oh
perfect I'm going to get yelled at for
that later but that's
okay well thank you thank you so much um
for coming on to the hustle Zone and and
um it was it was a pleasure to to to to
to hear from you and and to learn you
know you know you're a pretty good guy
and I think that you have really clear
you have a really clear understanding of
of what you know and it comes it comes
across clearly and I think um like I
said there's an invitation for you to
come back to you know to get deeper into
leadership and and whatnot maybe we
could put some you know free courses
together quick courses is for the hustle
Zone and you know to help us or to help
you you know promote um you know what
you're doing you know I'd be happy to to
do that with you so uh thank you so much
for coming in onto the hustle Zone my
friend absolutely and if anybody you
know out there wants to connect with us
further you know our website's I Amwell
fed.com so if anybody wants to hop over
there they can connect with me my you
know contact us and all of that's good
that's awesome and um you know folks
uh thank you guys for sharing today
again if anyone's in the live talk
Nations please share it over there um I
share this broadcast over there because
like H they Banned Me from sharing um I
guess apparently it's spam and I hate it
but uh thank you Ashley thank you
Anthony thank you will uh thank you
Susan day um um the Uriel
um um and who else was in here
and a few others yeah thank you I can't
see you guys right now for some reason
here oh
L yeah so Susan day said thank you for
your service uh we had a few people
saying thank you for your service
welcome so um yeah that's pretty much it
but thank you so much and I'll talk to
you guys later folks make sure you guys
buy yourself a hustle own t-shirt go to
hustles own.
remember October 1st is when we have the
husto mag it's a video mag um you know
that discusses
entrepreneurialism and um and expands
the crop it just shows people you know
beyond you know what we the pretty
picture that we see so um and it doesn't
always have to be negative you know it's
just you know some people want more
information and and it's and I think
people learn from hearing real people
talk about real people things and um
again thank Our Guest uh for for coming
and I'll talk to you guys
later and make sure you guys like my
page hustle Zone TV go to the hustle
Zone because all the content once the
magazine launches is all going to be
there so and if you know anybody that
wants to be on the hustle Zone show
please tell them to hit me up and I will
get them on to the show and we do this
every night 11:00 p.m. Eastern stand
Standard Time thank you guys so much and
one love